<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Review on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</title>
    <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/categories/book-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Review on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dmacleod.ca/ra/categories/book-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Last ballad by Wiley Cash</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/last-ballad-by-wiley-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/last-ballad-by-wiley-cash/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cash, Wiley
Title: The last ballad: A novel
Publication: New York, NY : William Morrow, an imprint of HarperCollins Publishers, 2017. ISBN 9780062682031.
DAISY audio format narrated by Karen Elizabeth White and Elizabeth Wiley. CELA library call number DA54667. 384 pages in the paper edition; 14 hrs., 7 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is a very moving story about, Ella Mae Wiggins, a striker and songwriter who took part in the 1929 textile mill strikes in the Southern United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Itsuka by Joy Kogawa</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/itsuka-by-joy-kogawa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/itsuka-by-joy-kogawa/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Kogawa, Joy
Title: Itsuka
Publication: Toronto, Ont. : Viking, 1992. ISBN 0140169881.
DAISY audio format narrated by Sandra Scott. CELA library call number DA12414. 288 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 45 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the sequel to Obasan, which I reviewed earlier.
I must say that, at this point, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it holds a candle to the original but then it did not benefit from Joy Kogawa&amp;rsquo;s luminous reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A discovery of witches by Deborah E. Harkness (All souls trilogy)</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/a-discovery-of-witches-by-deborah-e-harkness-all-souls-trilogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/a-discovery-of-witches-by-deborah-e-harkness-all-souls-trilogy/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Harkness, Deborah E., 1965-
Title: A discovery of witches; Series: All souls trilogy
 A discovery of witches (DA41609, ISBN9780670022410), 2011, read by Imogen Church (579 pages ; 25 hours, 31 minutes) Shadow of the night (DA45810, ISBN9780670023486), 2012, read by Karina Fernandez (584 pages ; 25 hours, 22 minutes) The book of life (DA49922, ISBN9780670025596 ), 2014, read by Jennifer Ikeda (561 pages; 23 hours, 55 minutes)  Publication: New York : Viking, 2011, 2012 &amp;amp; 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The back of the turtle by Thomas King</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-back-of-the-turtle-by-thomas-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-back-of-the-turtle-by-thomas-king/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: King, Thomas, 1943-
Title: The back of the turtle.
Publication: Toronto : HarperCollins Canada, 2014. ISBN 9781443431620.
DAISY audio format narrated by Jennifer Coffey. CELA library call number DA50031. 518 pages in the paper edition; 11 hrs., 41 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Set in the near future, following an apocalyptic environmental disaster, this is the story of a CEO, a scientist and a young First Nations artist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six degrés de liberté de Nicolas Dickner</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/six-degres-de-liberte-de-nicolas-dickner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/six-degres-de-liberte-de-nicolas-dickner/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Dickner, Nicolas, 1972-
Title: Six degrés de liberté
Publication: Québec (Québec) : Alto, 2015. ISBN 9782896942183.
DAISY audio format narrated by an anonymous narrator. CELA library call number DA98488. 380 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 40 mins. as a recorded book.
À propos Il s&amp;rsquo;agit d&amp;rsquo;une histoire très moderne qui se déroule au Québec pour la plupart mais aussi en Europe. Il est écrit en français.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The break by Katherena Vermette</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-break-by-katherena-vermette/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-break-by-katherena-vermette/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Vermette, Katherena, 1977-
Title: The break
Publication: Toronto : House of Anansi Press, 2016. ISBN 9781487001117.
DAISY audio format narrated by Diane Mackay. CELA library call number DA52503. 299 pages in the paper edition; 11 hrs., 38 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story An emotional but difficult read, this is the story of a Métis family in Winnipeg&amp;rsquo;s North end, near an undeveloped section called the Break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool water by Dianne Warren</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/cool-water-by-dianne-warren/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/cool-water-by-dianne-warren/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Warren, Dianne, 1950-
Title: Cool water by Dianne Warren
Publication: Toronto : HarperCollins Canada, 2009. ISBN 9781554685585.
DAISY audio format narrated by Kathleen Miller. CELA library call number DA38309. 328 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 50 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Set in the small town of Juliet, Saskatchewan, this book is a series of short stories that, together, build a multi-dimensional picture of the town&amp;rsquo;s inhabitants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La fiancée américaine d&#39;Éric Dupont</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/la-fiancee-americaine-eric-dupont/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/la-fiancee-americaine-eric-dupont/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Dupont, Éric, 1970-
Title: La fiancée américaine : roman
Publication: Montréal : Marchand de feuilles, 2012. ISBN 9782923896151.
DAISY audio format narrated by an unidentified narrator. CELA library call number DA96940. 557 pages in the paper edition; 25 hrs., 23 mins. as a recorded book.
À propos Une soirée du temps des fêtes à Rivière-du-Loup, Louis « le Cheval » Lamontagne raconte l&amp;rsquo;histoire de sa naissance à ses trois enfants tout en buvant du gin, en écoutant le chapelet à la radio, et en guettant le retour de sa femme de « chez les soeurs ».</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven stones to stand or fall by Diana Gabaldon</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/seven-stones-to-stand-or-fall-by-diana-gabaldon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/seven-stones-to-stand-or-fall-by-diana-gabaldon/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Gabaldon, Diana
Title: Seven stones to stand or fall: A collection of Outlander fiction.
Publication: New York : Delacorte Press, 2017. ISBN 9781501932601.
DAISY audio format narrated by Jeff Woodman, Davina Porter, Allan Scott-Douglas, Robert Ian Mackenzie. CELA library call number DA54159. 544 pages in the paper edition; 24 hrs., 20 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story If you are unfamiliar with Diana Gabaldon&amp;rsquo;s Outlander series, they are very enjoyable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsettling Canada by Arthur Manuel</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/unsettling-canada-by-arthur-manuel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/unsettling-canada-by-arthur-manuel/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Manuel, Arthur with Grand Chief Ronald M. Derrickson, forward by Naomi Klein
Title: Unsettling Canada : A national wake-up call
Publication: Toronto : Between the Lines, 2015. ISBN 9781771131766.
DAISY audio format narrated by Ken Luginbuhl. CELA library call number DA50988. 266 pages in the paper edition; 12 hrs., 8 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Arthur Manuel has been on the front lines of the battle for the recognition of indigenous rights, and specifically aboriginal title to the land, all his life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The story of Owen, dragon slayer of Trondheim</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-story-of-owen-dragon-slayer-of-trondheim-by-ek-johnston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-story-of-owen-dragon-slayer-of-trondheim-by-ek-johnston/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Johnston, E. K.
Title: The story of Owen : Dragon slayer of Trondheim
Publication: Minneapolis : Carolrhoda Lab, [2014]. ISBN 9781467710664.
DAISY audio format. 305 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 25 mins. as a recorded book. Not available through CELA.
About the story This is a Canadian book, set in Southwestern Ontario on the shores of Lake Huron. Picture an epic battle between a dragon and its Slayer … on the Burlington Skyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loch Bras d&#39;Or by Margaret MacPhail</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/loch-bras-dor-by-margaret-macphail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/loch-bras-dor-by-margaret-macphail/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: MacPhail, Margaret, 1887-1976
Title: Loch Bras d&amp;rsquo;Or
Publication: Windsor, N.S. : Lancelot Press, 1970. ISBN number not available.
DAISY audio format narrated by Mary Delaney. CELA library call number DA45504. 163 pages in the paper edition; 6 hrs., 46 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Why did I enjoy this book? The narrator, Mary Delaney: she was superb!
The book itself is chronicles two families in the Cape Breton of the 1880s, one Protestant and the other Catholic (Barra).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obasan-by-joy-kogawa</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/obasan-by-joy-kogawa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/obasan-by-joy-kogawa/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Kogawa, Joy
Title: Obasan.
Publication: Toronto : Lester &amp;amp; Orpen Dennys, 1981. ISBN 0-919630-42-1.
DAISY audio format narrated by the author. CELA library call number DA03222. 250 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 51 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Beautifully read by the author, Obasan tells the story of the internment of Japanese-Canadians during the Second World War.
Her narrator, Naomi Nakane (pronounced na-kaan-neh), is a middle-aged schoolteacher on the Canadian prairies at the time the story opens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No time to spare by Ursula K. Le Guin</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/no-spare-time-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/no-spare-time-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Le Guin, Ursula K., 1929-
Title: No time to spare : Thinking about what matters
Publication: Boston : Houghton Mifflin Harcourt, 2017. ISBN 9781328661593.
Not yet available in DAISY format. 280 pages in the paper edition.
About the story I read this book in pre-publication, in PDF format, using NVDA.
This book is the &amp;ldquo;the best of&amp;rdquo; Ursula K. Le Guin’s blog, which I have been loving for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young Wizards series by Diane Duane</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/young-wizards-series-by-diane-duane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/young-wizards-series-by-diane-duane/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Duane, Diane
Title: So you want to be a wizard.
Publication: San Diego, Calif.: Harcourt Brace &amp;amp; Co., 1983. ISBN 9781449880378.
DAISY audio format narrated by Christina Moore. CELA library call number DA46572. 369 pages in the paper edition; 7 hrs., 24 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the first in an excellent series of books that follow the adventures of Nina (aged 13) and Kit, short for Christopher, who is a year younger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chief Inspector Barnaby mysteries by Caroline Graham</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/chief-inspector-barnaby-mysteries-by-caroline-graham/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/chief-inspector-barnaby-mysteries-by-caroline-graham/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Graham, Caroline, 1931-
Title: The killings at Badger&amp;rsquo;s Drift Publication: London : Headline Book Publishing, 1989. ISBN 9780755342150. DAISY audio format narrated by Hugh Ross. CELA library call number DA31505. 264 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 26 mins. as a recorded book.
Title: A ghost in the machine. Publication: London : Headline, 2004. ISBN 0755307704. DAISY audio format narrated by Terri Cherniak. CELA library call number DA26166.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flavia de Luce books by Alan Bradley</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/flavia-de-luce-books-by-alan-bradley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/flavia-de-luce-books-by-alan-bradley/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Bradley, Alan C., 1938-
Title: The sweetness at the bottom of the pie.
Publication: New York : Bantam, 2009. ISBN 9780553840766.
DAISY audio format narrated by Annabel Bates. CELA library call number DA38056. 292 pages in the paper edition; 11 hrs., 9 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story If you have never read the Flavia de Luce (that&amp;rsquo;s Flavia with an eh) books, you are in for a wildly hilarious treat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The untold by Courtney Collins</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-untold-by-courtney-collins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-untold-by-courtney-collins/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Collins, Courtney.
Title: The untold
Publication: New York : Amy Einhorn Books, Published by G.P. Putnam&amp;rsquo;s Sons, a member of Penguin Group (USA), 2014. ISBN 9780399167096.
DAISY audio format narrated by the author. CELA library call number DA49956. 288 pages in the paper edition; 6 hrs., 56 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Based on the true story of Elizabeth Jessie Hickman, a woman who rustled cattle and escaped a brutal life, fleeing into the wilderness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural order by Brian Francis</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/natural-order-by-brian-francis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/natural-order-by-brian-francis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Francis, Brian, 1971-
Title: Natural order
Publication: Toronto : Doubleday Canada, 2011. ISBN 9780385671538.
DAISY audio format narrated by Bennett McCardle. CELA library call number DA41407. 361 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 39 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the beautifully moving life story of an 86-year-old woman named Joyce. Told in a series of flash-backs from her early girlhood in rural Southern Ontario, through her marriage and family life, to her widowhood and eventual death, it shows the evolution of a life filled with regret and fear of what the neighbours will think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s explore diabetes with owls by David Sedaris</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/lets-explore-diabetes-with-owls-by-david-sedaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/lets-explore-diabetes-with-owls-by-david-sedaris/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Sedaris, David.
Title: Let&amp;rsquo;s explore diabetes with owls: Essays, etc.
Publication: New York, NY : Little, Brown and Company, 2013. ISBN 9780316154697.
DAISY audio format narrated by David Sedaris. CELA library call number DA53190. 275 pages in the paper edition; 6 hrs., 26 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is a series of essays, read by the author and recorded at various times, some recorded live, some in studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norse mythology by Neil Gaiman</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/norse-mythology-by-neil-gaiman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/norse-mythology-by-neil-gaiman/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Gaiman, Neil
Title: Norse mythology
Publication: New York : W.W. Norton &amp;amp; Company, 2017. ISBN 9780393609097.
DAISY audio format narrated by the author. CELA library call number DA53608. 304 pages in the paper edition; 6 hrs., 30 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Published this year (2017) and read by the author, this is a straight-forward re-telling of the stories of Norse mythology: Odin, Baldur, Freya, Thor, Hod and — of course — Loki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peace pipe dreams by Darrell Dennis</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/peace-pipe-dreams-by-darrell-dennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/peace-pipe-dreams-by-darrell-dennis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Dennis, Darrell (Darrell Michael).
Title: Peace pipe dreams : The truth about lies about Indians.
Publication: Madeira Park, British Columbia : Douglas &amp;amp; McIntyre, 2014. ISBN 9781771000406.
DAISY audio format narrated by Bruce McLeod. CELA library call number DA50486. 240 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 8 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Everyone should read this book.
Winner of First Nation Communities Read 2015-2016, Shushwap writer Darrel Dennis starts out with some &amp;ldquo;myth-busting&amp;rdquo;, humourously debunking some popularly-held mainstream stereotypes about indigenous people in Canada: drunken Indians, lazy Indians, no taxes, free schooling and housing, that they get a free ride&amp;hellip; there are so very many.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The last Neanderthal by Clarie Cameron</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-last-neanderthal-by-clarie-cameron/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-last-neanderthal-by-clarie-cameron/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cameron, Claire, 1973-
Title: The last Neanderthal.
Publication: City : Press, year.Toronto : Doubleday Canada, 2017. ISBN 9780385686785.
276 pages in the print edition.
About the story This is a forthcoming book, which I read as a galley proof. I used the Adobe Digital Editions reader to read this DRM e-book, with NVDA (NonVisual Desktop Access) a by-donation screen reader that allows blind and visually-impaired people use computers and the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosstalk by Connie Willis</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/crosstalk-by-connie-willis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/crosstalk-by-connie-willis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Willis, Connie.
Title: Crosstalk.
Publication: New York : Del Rey, [2016]. ISBN 9780345540676.
DAISY audio format narrated by Mia Barron. CELA library call number DA52655. 498 pages in the paper edition; 18 hrs., 45 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This book follows the adventures of young Briddey Flanagan, an Irish-American woman living in a modern day where doctors have the ability to surgically increase empathy between romantic partners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cherry Cola book club by Ashton Lee</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-cherry-cola-book-club-by-ashton-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-cherry-cola-book-club-by-ashton-lee/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author:
Title: The Cherry Cola book club. Series: Cherry Cola Book Club ; 1
Publication: New York : Kensington Pub. Corp., 2013. ISBN 9780758273413.
DAISY audio format narrated by Marguerite Gavin. CELA library call number DA52856. 260 pages in the print edition; 7 hrs., 40 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story I picked this one up because it was the first in a series. I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t, because the title seemed a bit twee, but obviously I changed my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overclocked by Cory Doctorow</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/overclocked-by-cory-doctorow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/overclocked-by-cory-doctorow/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author:
Title: Overclocked : Stories of the future present
Publication: New York : Thunder&amp;rsquo;s Mouth Press, 2007. ISBN 9781560259817.
DAISY audio format narrated by Lloyd James, Nicola Barber, R. C. Bray, Fiona Hardingham, Jeffrey Kafer, Jim Meskimen and Emily Woo Zeller. CELA library call number DA52551. 285 pages in the print edition; 13 hrs., 14 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story I love the way Cory Doctorow explores the present through the lens of potential futures and alternate realities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Les yeux jaunes des crocodiles de Katherine Pancol</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/les-yeux-jaunes-des-crocodiles-de-katherine-pancol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/les-yeux-jaunes-des-crocodiles-de-katherine-pancol/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Pancol, Katherine, 1954-
Title: Les yeux jaunes des crocodiles : roman
Publication: Paris : Albin Michel, 2006. ISBN 9782226169983.
DAISY audio format narrated by Anne Cartier. CELA library call number DA97648. 651 pages in the print edition; 18 hrs., 10 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This book is also available in English under the title The Yellow Eyes of Crocodiles, although not through the CELA library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master of space and time by Rudy Rucker</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/master-of-space-and-time-by-rudy-rucker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/master-of-space-and-time-by-rudy-rucker/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Rucker, Rudy v. B. (Rudy von Bitter), 1946-
Title: Master of space and time
Publication: New York : Baen, 1984. ISBN 978-1433207693.
DAISY audio format narrated by John Ihrig. CELA library call number DC05893. 229 pages; 5hrs., 15mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This CELA book was transferred from the original audiocassette. This means that there is no DAISY navigation beyond the 90-minute bookmarks, which bear no relation to the contents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magruder&#39;s curiosity cabinet by HP Wood</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/magruders-curiosity-cabinet-by-hp-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/magruders-curiosity-cabinet-by-hp-wood/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Wood, H. P. (Hilary Poole).
Title: Magruder&amp;rsquo;s curiosity cabinet.
Publication: Naperville, IL : Sourcebooks Landmark, 2016. ISBN 9781501908415.
DAISY audio format narrated by Nancy Wu. CELA library call number DA52319. 368 pages in the print edition; 13 hrs., 1 min. as a recorded book.
About the story I had no idea what to expect from this book, and I must say: I&amp;rsquo;m delighted!
Set in the amusement parks of Coney Island in 1904, the main characters are the sideshow &amp;ldquo;freaks&amp;rdquo; and their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real murders by Charlaine Harris</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/real-murders-by-charlaine-harris/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/real-murders-by-charlaine-harris/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Harris, Charlaine.
Title: Real murders : an Aurora Teagarden mystery
Publication: New York : Berkley Prime Crime, 2007. ISBN 9781456111700.
DAISY audio format narrated by Thérèse Plummer. CELA library call number DA47376. 290 pages in the paperback edition; 6 hrs., 9 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the first novel in a series of murder-mysteries featuring Aurora Teagarden, a library worker who &amp;ndash; in this one at least &amp;ndash; belongs to a sort of book club slash fan club on real murders (as in, analysing how famous murders of the past were done and theorising whodunnit).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Penguin anthology of Canadian humour by Will Ferguson</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-penguin-anthology-of-canadian-humour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-penguin-anthology-of-canadian-humour/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Ferguson, Will
Title: The Penguin anthology of Canadian humour
Publication: Toronto : Viking Canada, 2006. ISBN 9780670064434.
DAISY audio format narrated by Barbara Lord and Chris Caughey. CELA library call number DA28565. 496 pages in the print edition; 16 hrs., 45 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This anthology, compiled by Will Ferguson and originally published in 2006, is a veritable Who’s Who of Canadian humour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Woefield Farm books by Susan Juby</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-woefield-farm-books-by-susan-juby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-woefield-farm-books-by-susan-juby/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Juby, Susan (1969-)
Title: The Woefield poultry collective. Publication: New York : HarperCollins Canada, 2011. ISBN 9781554687442. DAISY audio format narrated by Jennifer Coffey. CELA library call number DA39138. 306 pages; 9hrs., 13mins. as a recorded book.
Title: Republic of Dirt: a return to Woefield Farm. Publication: Toronto : HarperAvenue 2015. ISBN 9781443423960. DAISY audio format narrated by Taina Makinen and Henry LaCroix. CELA library call number DA52124.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Swallow: A ghost story by Charis Cotter</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-swallow-a-ghost-story-by-charis-cotter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-swallow-a-ghost-story-by-charis-cotter/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cotter, Charis.
Title: The swallow : A ghost story
Publication: Toronto : Tundra Books, 2014. ISBN 9781770495913.
DAISY audio format available on Bookshare. It is not available on the CELA library (yet). 320 pages in the paper edition.
About the story OK, I fell off the blogging wagon for a bit, there.
Ironically, it was Ursula K. LeGuin&amp;rsquo;s WONDERFUL collection of novellas, The Found and the Lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The hum and the shiver by Alex Bledsoe</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-hum-and-the-shiver-by-alex-bledsoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-hum-and-the-shiver-by-alex-bledsoe/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Bledsoe, Alex.
Title: The hum and the shiver.
Publication: New York : Tor Books, 2011. ISBN 9781455113965.
DAISY audio format narrated by Emily Janice Card and Stefan Rudnicki. CELA library call number DC52543. 349 pages in the paperback edition; 9 hrs., 44 mins. as a recorded book.
Title: The hum and the shiver.
Publication: New York : Tor Books, 2013. ISBN 9781482915600.
DAISY audio format narrated by Stefan Rudnicki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American boy by Andrew Taylor</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/american-boy-by-andrew-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/american-boy-by-andrew-taylor/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Taylor, Andrew (1951- ).
Title: The American boy.
Publication: London : Flamingo, 2003. ISBN 000710961X.
DAISY audio format narrated by Alex Jennings. CELA library call number DA29862. 400 pages in paper format; 16 hrs., 45 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Edgar Allan Poe is the eponymous American Boy, but he is really a secondary character in the novel. He ties the actors together, but he does not play a crucial role by his actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The virgin cure by Ami McKay</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/virgin-cure-by-ami-mckay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/virgin-cure-by-ami-mckay/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: McKay, Ami
Title: The virgin cure
Publication: Toronto : Knopf Canada, 2010. ISBN 9780676979565.
DAISY audio format narrated by Jennifer Coffey. CELA library call number DA41472. 368 pages in the hardcover edition; 9 hrs., 30 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story I read Ami McKay&amp;rsquo;s first book, The birth House, many years ago and loved it. This is her second novel.
Set in New York city in 1871, the book follows the life of a young girl named Moth who lives in poverty with her mother on Christie Street, a poor area without sewers where people live in squalor as they can and die when they can no longer hold the tatters of their lives together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dispossessed: An ambiguous utopia by Ursula K. Le Guin</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-dispossessed-an-ambiguous-utopia-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-dispossessed-an-ambiguous-utopia-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Le Guin, Ursula K., 1929-
Title: The dispossessed: An ambiguous utopia
Publication: New York : Harper &amp;amp; Row, [1974]. ISBN 0060125632.
DAISY audio format narrated by Lloyd Scott. CELA library call number DC03870. 341 pages in the paperback edition; 12 hrs., 9 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Set in Le Guin&amp;rsquo;s Hainish universe, this is the story of a physicist born into a radically democratic society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thornyhold by Mary Stewart</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/thornyhold-by-mary-stewart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/thornyhold-by-mary-stewart/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Stewart, Mary.
Title: Thornyhold.
Publication: London ; Toronto : Hodder &amp;amp; Stoughton, 1988. ISBN 0688084257.
DAISY audio format narrated by Pauline Munro. CELA library call number DA33092. 224 pages in the paperback edition; 6 hrs., 59 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story The first thing I want to say about this book is that it was way, way too short. I really enjoyed it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mme Proust and the kosher kitchen</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/mme-proust-and-the-kosher-kitchen-by-kate-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/mme-proust-and-the-kosher-kitchen-by-kate-taylor/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Taylor, Kate
Title: Mme Proust and the kosher kitchen.
Publication: [Toronto] : Doubleday Canada, c2003. ISBN 978-0701173746.
DAISY audio format narrated by Nicki Scrimger. CELA library call number DA25030. 414 pages in the hardcover edition; 15 hrs., 41 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story I picked up this book because Kate Taylor, a Canadian author, has a new book coming out soon. The new one, Serial monogamy, will not be available on CELA for several more months, so I downloaded this one to try instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Pettigrew&#39;s last stand</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/major-pettigrews-last-stand-by-helen-simonson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/major-pettigrews-last-stand-by-helen-simonson/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Simonson, Helen.
Title: Major Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s last stand.
Publication: [Toronto] : Bond Street Books, c2010. ISBN 9781408804254.
DAISY audio format narrated by Stephen Thorne. CELA library call number DA41307. 358 pages in the paperback edition; 12 hrs., 39 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Author Helen Simonson&amp;rsquo;s debut novel, Major Pettigrew&amp;rsquo;s Last Stand is a delightful read.
The main character, Major Ernest Pettigrew (retired), lives alone in the small Sussex village of Edgecombe St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legends: Short novels by the masters of modern fantasy (volume 1, 1998)</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/legends-short-novels-by-the-masters-of-modern-fantasy-volume-1-1998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/legends-short-novels-by-the-masters-of-modern-fantasy-volume-1-1998/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Silverberg, Robert. (ed.)
Title: Legends: Short novels by the masters of modern fantasy. Volume 1, 1998.
Publication: New York, NY : Tor Fantasy, 1998. ISBN 0312867875.
DAISY audio format narrated by Kristin Allison. CELA library call number DA20360. 715 pages in the paper edition; 25 hrs., 29 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Now, if you are trying to get a feel for science fiction and fantasy at the end of the 1990s, this is an excellent beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Cathcart&#39;s greek philosopher joke books</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/thomas-cathcarts-greek-philosopher-joke-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/thomas-cathcarts-greek-philosopher-joke-books/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cathcart, Thomas (1940- ) and Daniel Klein.
Title: Plato and a platypus walk into a bar&amp;hellip;: Understanding philosophy through jokes. (2006)
Publication: New York : Abrams Image, 2006. ISBN 9781456102821.
DAISY audio format narrated by Johnny Heller. CELA library call number DC46041. 224 pages in the paperback edition; 4 hrs., 9 min. as a recorded book.
Title: Aristotle and an aardvark go to Washington: Understanding political doublespeak through philosophy and jokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindred by Octavia E. Butler</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/kindred-by-octavia-e-butler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/kindred-by-octavia-e-butler/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Butler, Octavia E. (1947-2006)
Title: Kindred.
Publication: Boston : Beacon Press, 2003. ISBN 9781449876814.
DAISY audio format narrated by Kim Staunton. CELA library call number DA46431. 306 pages in the paperback edition; 10 hrs., 55 min. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the story of Dana, a young African-American woman living in California in 1976, who is mysteriously and uncontrollably called to Maryland, circa 1815, to save the life of a white slave-owner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The other queen by Philippa Gregory</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-other-queen-by-philippa-gregory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-other-queen-by-philippa-gregory/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Gregory, Philippa
Title: The other queen
Publication: London : HarperCollins, 2008. ISBN 9780007190348.
DAISY audio format narrated by Anne Glatt and Marc Rosen. CELA library call number DC34129. 442 pages in the paperback edition; 13 hrs., 37 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Set in the 16th century England of Elizabeth I, this historical novel tells the story of Mary, Queen of Scots (1542-1587).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lavinia by Ursula K. Le Guin</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/lavinia-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/lavinia-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Le Guin, Ursula K.
Title: Lavinia
Publication: Orlando : Harcourt, 2008. ISBN 9781456106621.
DAISY audio format narrated by Alyssa Bresnahan. CELA library call number DA47766. 293 pages in the paperback edition, 11 hrs., 39 min. as a recorded book.
About the story Ursula K. Le Guin has been one of my favourite authors ever since I encountered her Earthsea books as a young girl. They were among the books I could not wait to read to my daughter when she was younger, and they hold a special place in my heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Julia speaks her mind by Ann B. Ross</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/miss-julia-speaks-her-mind-by-ann-b-ross/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/miss-julia-speaks-her-mind-by-ann-b-ross/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Ross, Ann B.
Title: Miss Julia speaks her mind
Publication: William Morrow, 2000. ISBN 9780061978302.
DAISY audio format narrated by Terry Hayes Sales. CELA library call number DA22137. 290 pages in the paperback edition, 8 hrs., 38 min. as a recorded book.
About the story In this, the first book in the Miss Julia series, the narrator Miss Julia jumps right in and tells the story of her small, Southern US town in the 1950s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burning Bright by Tracy Chevalier</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/burning-bright-by-tracy-chevalier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/burning-bright-by-tracy-chevalier/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Chevalier, Tracy.
Title: Burning bright.
Publication: New York : Dutton, 2007. 9780525949787 (hardcover)
DAISY audio format narrated by Jill Tanner. CELA library call number DA480602007. 417 pages in the paperback edition, 11 hrs., 26 min. as a recorded book.
About the story After suffering a tragic loss, a Dorsetshire family moves to Georgian-era London at the invitation of a circus owner. Setting up a chair-making workshop in their small upstairs apartment, the Kellaway family set about making a new life for themselves, encountering colourful neighbours such as the publisher and artist William Blake, the streetwise Maggie Butterfield and the mesmerising circus owner Philip Astley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five minds of the future by Robert Gardner</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/five-minds-for-the-future-by-howard-gardner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/five-minds-for-the-future-by-howard-gardner/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Gardner, Howard. Title: Five minds for the future. Publication: Boston, Mass. : Harvard Business School Press, c2007. ISBN 9781591399124.
196 pages in the paper edition; 6hrs., 15 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story American developmental psychologist Howard Gardner, Hobbs Professor of Cognition and Education at the Harvard Graduate School of Education, wrote this book to describe the intellectual skills and the type of learning he thinks will be necessary to succeed in the workplace of the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian copyright: A citizen&#39;s guide</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/canadian-copyright-a-citizens-guide-by-laura-murray/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/canadian-copyright-a-citizens-guide-by-laura-murray/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Murray, Laura J. with Samuel E. Trosow
Title: Canadian copyright: A citizen&amp;rsquo;s guide. (2nd edition)
Publication: Toronto : Between the Lines, 2013. ISBN 9781771130134.
About the book I initially read the first edition of this book in 2007. I was struck by how clearly the authors explained the history of copyright in Canada. They clearly demonstrate how that history informs Canadian law, and how the law informs the practice of individuals and groups across our society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UContent by Nicholas Toaiuolo</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/ucontent-by-nicholas-tomaiuolo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/ucontent-by-nicholas-tomaiuolo/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Tomaiuolos, Nicholas G.
Title: UContent: The information professional&amp;rsquo;s guide to user-generated content.
Publication: Medford, N.J.: Information Today, 2012. 340p. ISBN 9781573874250
About the book User-education librarian and information-literacy instructor Nicholas Tomaiuolo presents an overview of the major &amp;ldquo;Web 2.0&amp;rdquo; resources and how librarians might and have used them.
Because of the fungible nature of his material, he provides a companion website which he commits to updating with resources as they move or become available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some great idea by Edward Keenan</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/some-great-idea-by-edward-keenan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/some-great-idea-by-edward-keenan/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Keenan, Edward
Title: Some great idea: good neighbourhoods, crazy politics and the invention of Toronto.
Publication: Toronto : Coach House Books, c2013. 175 p. ISBN: 9781552452660.
About the book This small, readable book by Toronto journalist Edward Keenan did something I thought could never happen &amp;ndash; it made the election of Toronto mayor Rob Ford almost make sense!
Starting with a number &amp;ldquo;Toronto stories&amp;rdquo;, including his meeting with then-Councillor Rob Ford in 2006, Keenan uses story to describe different facets and ways of life the city of Toronto.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>