<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Women on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</title>
    <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/tags/women/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Women on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://StackSquirrel.github.io/tags/women/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Last ballad by Wiley Cash</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/last-ballad-by-wiley-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/last-ballad-by-wiley-cash/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cash, Wiley
Title: The last ballad: A novel
Publication: New York, NY : William Morrow, an imprint of HarperCollins Publishers, 2017. ISBN 9780062682031.
DAISY audio format narrated by Karen Elizabeth White and Elizabeth Wiley. CELA library call number DA54667. 384 pages in the paper edition; 14 hrs., 7 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is a very moving story about, Ella Mae Wiggins, a striker and songwriter who took part in the 1929 textile mill strikes in the Southern United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A discovery of witches by Deborah E. Harkness (All souls trilogy)</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/a-discovery-of-witches-by-deborah-e-harkness-all-souls-trilogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/a-discovery-of-witches-by-deborah-e-harkness-all-souls-trilogy/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Harkness, Deborah E., 1965-
Title: A discovery of witches; Series: All souls trilogy
 A discovery of witches (DA41609, ISBN9780670022410), 2011, read by Imogen Church (579 pages ; 25 hours, 31 minutes) Shadow of the night (DA45810, ISBN9780670023486), 2012, read by Karina Fernandez (584 pages ; 25 hours, 22 minutes) The book of life (DA49922, ISBN9780670025596 ), 2014, read by Jennifer Ikeda (561 pages; 23 hours, 55 minutes)  Publication: New York : Viking, 2011, 2012 &amp;amp; 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The break by Katherena Vermette</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-break-by-katherena-vermette/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-break-by-katherena-vermette/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Vermette, Katherena, 1977-
Title: The break
Publication: Toronto : House of Anansi Press, 2016. ISBN 9781487001117.
DAISY audio format narrated by Diane Mackay. CELA library call number DA52503. 299 pages in the paper edition; 11 hrs., 38 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story An emotional but difficult read, this is the story of a Métis family in Winnipeg&amp;rsquo;s North end, near an undeveloped section called the Break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ursula K. Le Guin (October 21, 1929, to January 22, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/ursula-k-le-guin-october-21-1929-to-january-22-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/ursula-k-le-guin-october-21-1929-to-january-22-2018/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Hard times are coming, when we&amp;rsquo;ll be wanting the voices of writers who can see alternatives to how we live now, can see through our fear-stricken society and its obsessive technologies to other ways of being, and even imagine real grounds for hope. We&amp;rsquo;ll need writers who can remember freedom &amp;ndash; poets, visionaries &amp;ndash; realists of a larger reality.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; From Ursula K. Le Guin&amp;rsquo;s acceptance speech, National Book Awards, 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La fiancée américaine d&#39;Éric Dupont</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/la-fiancee-americaine-eric-dupont/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/la-fiancee-americaine-eric-dupont/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Dupont, Éric, 1970-
Title: La fiancée américaine : roman
Publication: Montréal : Marchand de feuilles, 2012. ISBN 9782923896151.
DAISY audio format narrated by an unidentified narrator. CELA library call number DA96940. 557 pages in the paper edition; 25 hrs., 23 mins. as a recorded book.
À propos Une soirée du temps des fêtes à Rivière-du-Loup, Louis « le Cheval » Lamontagne raconte l&amp;rsquo;histoire de sa naissance à ses trois enfants tout en buvant du gin, en écoutant le chapelet à la radio, et en guettant le retour de sa femme de « chez les soeurs ».</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven stones to stand or fall by Diana Gabaldon</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/seven-stones-to-stand-or-fall-by-diana-gabaldon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/seven-stones-to-stand-or-fall-by-diana-gabaldon/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Gabaldon, Diana
Title: Seven stones to stand or fall: A collection of Outlander fiction.
Publication: New York : Delacorte Press, 2017. ISBN 9781501932601.
DAISY audio format narrated by Jeff Woodman, Davina Porter, Allan Scott-Douglas, Robert Ian Mackenzie. CELA library call number DA54159. 544 pages in the paper edition; 24 hrs., 20 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story If you are unfamiliar with Diana Gabaldon&amp;rsquo;s Outlander series, they are very enjoyable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The story of Owen, dragon slayer of Trondheim</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-story-of-owen-dragon-slayer-of-trondheim-by-ek-johnston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-story-of-owen-dragon-slayer-of-trondheim-by-ek-johnston/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Johnston, E. K.
Title: The story of Owen : Dragon slayer of Trondheim
Publication: Minneapolis : Carolrhoda Lab, [2014]. ISBN 9781467710664.
DAISY audio format. 305 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 25 mins. as a recorded book. Not available through CELA.
About the story This is a Canadian book, set in Southwestern Ontario on the shores of Lake Huron. Picture an epic battle between a dragon and its Slayer … on the Burlington Skyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loch Bras d&#39;Or by Margaret MacPhail</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/loch-bras-dor-by-margaret-macphail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/loch-bras-dor-by-margaret-macphail/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: MacPhail, Margaret, 1887-1976
Title: Loch Bras d&amp;rsquo;Or
Publication: Windsor, N.S. : Lancelot Press, 1970. ISBN number not available.
DAISY audio format narrated by Mary Delaney. CELA library call number DA45504. 163 pages in the paper edition; 6 hrs., 46 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Why did I enjoy this book? The narrator, Mary Delaney: she was superb!
The book itself is chronicles two families in the Cape Breton of the 1880s, one Protestant and the other Catholic (Barra).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obasan-by-joy-kogawa</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/obasan-by-joy-kogawa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/obasan-by-joy-kogawa/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Kogawa, Joy
Title: Obasan.
Publication: Toronto : Lester &amp;amp; Orpen Dennys, 1981. ISBN 0-919630-42-1.
DAISY audio format narrated by the author. CELA library call number DA03222. 250 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 51 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Beautifully read by the author, Obasan tells the story of the internment of Japanese-Canadians during the Second World War.
Her narrator, Naomi Nakane (pronounced na-kaan-neh), is a middle-aged schoolteacher on the Canadian prairies at the time the story opens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No time to spare by Ursula K. Le Guin</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/no-spare-time-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/no-spare-time-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Le Guin, Ursula K., 1929-
Title: No time to spare : Thinking about what matters
Publication: Boston : Houghton Mifflin Harcourt, 2017. ISBN 9781328661593.
Not yet available in DAISY format. 280 pages in the paper edition.
About the story I read this book in pre-publication, in PDF format, using NVDA.
This book is the &amp;ldquo;the best of&amp;rdquo; Ursula K. Le Guin’s blog, which I have been loving for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flavia de Luce books by Alan Bradley</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/flavia-de-luce-books-by-alan-bradley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/flavia-de-luce-books-by-alan-bradley/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Bradley, Alan C., 1938-
Title: The sweetness at the bottom of the pie.
Publication: New York : Bantam, 2009. ISBN 9780553840766.
DAISY audio format narrated by Annabel Bates. CELA library call number DA38056. 292 pages in the paper edition; 11 hrs., 9 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story If you have never read the Flavia de Luce (that&amp;rsquo;s Flavia with an eh) books, you are in for a wildly hilarious treat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The untold by Courtney Collins</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-untold-by-courtney-collins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-untold-by-courtney-collins/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Collins, Courtney.
Title: The untold
Publication: New York : Amy Einhorn Books, Published by G.P. Putnam&amp;rsquo;s Sons, a member of Penguin Group (USA), 2014. ISBN 9780399167096.
DAISY audio format narrated by the author. CELA library call number DA49956. 288 pages in the paper edition; 6 hrs., 56 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Based on the true story of Elizabeth Jessie Hickman, a woman who rustled cattle and escaped a brutal life, fleeing into the wilderness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural order by Brian Francis</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/natural-order-by-brian-francis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/natural-order-by-brian-francis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Francis, Brian, 1971-
Title: Natural order
Publication: Toronto : Doubleday Canada, 2011. ISBN 9780385671538.
DAISY audio format narrated by Bennett McCardle. CELA library call number DA41407. 361 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 39 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the beautifully moving life story of an 86-year-old woman named Joyce. Told in a series of flash-backs from her early girlhood in rural Southern Ontario, through her marriage and family life, to her widowhood and eventual death, it shows the evolution of a life filled with regret and fear of what the neighbours will think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The last Neanderthal by Clarie Cameron</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-last-neanderthal-by-clarie-cameron/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-last-neanderthal-by-clarie-cameron/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cameron, Claire, 1973-
Title: The last Neanderthal.
Publication: City : Press, year.Toronto : Doubleday Canada, 2017. ISBN 9780385686785.
276 pages in the print edition.
About the story This is a forthcoming book, which I read as a galley proof. I used the Adobe Digital Editions reader to read this DRM e-book, with NVDA (NonVisual Desktop Access) a by-donation screen reader that allows blind and visually-impaired people use computers and the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosstalk by Connie Willis</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/crosstalk-by-connie-willis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/crosstalk-by-connie-willis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Willis, Connie.
Title: Crosstalk.
Publication: New York : Del Rey, [2016]. ISBN 9780345540676.
DAISY audio format narrated by Mia Barron. CELA library call number DA52655. 498 pages in the paper edition; 18 hrs., 45 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This book follows the adventures of young Briddey Flanagan, an Irish-American woman living in a modern day where doctors have the ability to surgically increase empathy between romantic partners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cherry Cola book club by Ashton Lee</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-cherry-cola-book-club-by-ashton-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-cherry-cola-book-club-by-ashton-lee/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author:
Title: The Cherry Cola book club. Series: Cherry Cola Book Club ; 1
Publication: New York : Kensington Pub. Corp., 2013. ISBN 9780758273413.
DAISY audio format narrated by Marguerite Gavin. CELA library call number DA52856. 260 pages in the print edition; 7 hrs., 40 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story I picked this one up because it was the first in a series. I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t, because the title seemed a bit twee, but obviously I changed my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Les yeux jaunes des crocodiles de Katherine Pancol</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/les-yeux-jaunes-des-crocodiles-de-katherine-pancol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/les-yeux-jaunes-des-crocodiles-de-katherine-pancol/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Pancol, Katherine, 1954-
Title: Les yeux jaunes des crocodiles : roman
Publication: Paris : Albin Michel, 2006. ISBN 9782226169983.
DAISY audio format narrated by Anne Cartier. CELA library call number DA97648. 651 pages in the print edition; 18 hrs., 10 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This book is also available in English under the title The Yellow Eyes of Crocodiles, although not through the CELA library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magruder&#39;s curiosity cabinet by HP Wood</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/magruders-curiosity-cabinet-by-hp-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/magruders-curiosity-cabinet-by-hp-wood/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Wood, H. P. (Hilary Poole).
Title: Magruder&amp;rsquo;s curiosity cabinet.
Publication: Naperville, IL : Sourcebooks Landmark, 2016. ISBN 9781501908415.
DAISY audio format narrated by Nancy Wu. CELA library call number DA52319. 368 pages in the print edition; 13 hrs., 1 min. as a recorded book.
About the story I had no idea what to expect from this book, and I must say: I&amp;rsquo;m delighted!
Set in the amusement parks of Coney Island in 1904, the main characters are the sideshow &amp;ldquo;freaks&amp;rdquo; and their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Woefield Farm books by Susan Juby</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-woefield-farm-books-by-susan-juby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-woefield-farm-books-by-susan-juby/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Juby, Susan (1969-)
Title: The Woefield poultry collective. Publication: New York : HarperCollins Canada, 2011. ISBN 9781554687442. DAISY audio format narrated by Jennifer Coffey. CELA library call number DA39138. 306 pages; 9hrs., 13mins. as a recorded book.
Title: Republic of Dirt: a return to Woefield Farm. Publication: Toronto : HarperAvenue 2015. ISBN 9781443423960. DAISY audio format narrated by Taina Makinen and Henry LaCroix. CELA library call number DA52124.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Swallow: A ghost story by Charis Cotter</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-swallow-a-ghost-story-by-charis-cotter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-swallow-a-ghost-story-by-charis-cotter/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cotter, Charis.
Title: The swallow : A ghost story
Publication: Toronto : Tundra Books, 2014. ISBN 9781770495913.
DAISY audio format available on Bookshare. It is not available on the CELA library (yet). 320 pages in the paper edition.
About the story OK, I fell off the blogging wagon for a bit, there.
Ironically, it was Ursula K. LeGuin&amp;rsquo;s WONDERFUL collection of novellas, The Found and the Lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The virgin cure by Ami McKay</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/virgin-cure-by-ami-mckay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/virgin-cure-by-ami-mckay/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: McKay, Ami
Title: The virgin cure
Publication: Toronto : Knopf Canada, 2010. ISBN 9780676979565.
DAISY audio format narrated by Jennifer Coffey. CELA library call number DA41472. 368 pages in the hardcover edition; 9 hrs., 30 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story I read Ami McKay&amp;rsquo;s first book, The birth House, many years ago and loved it. This is her second novel.
Set in New York city in 1871, the book follows the life of a young girl named Moth who lives in poverty with her mother on Christie Street, a poor area without sewers where people live in squalor as they can and die when they can no longer hold the tatters of their lives together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thornyhold by Mary Stewart</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/thornyhold-by-mary-stewart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/thornyhold-by-mary-stewart/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Stewart, Mary.
Title: Thornyhold.
Publication: London ; Toronto : Hodder &amp;amp; Stoughton, 1988. ISBN 0688084257.
DAISY audio format narrated by Pauline Munro. CELA library call number DA33092. 224 pages in the paperback edition; 6 hrs., 59 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story The first thing I want to say about this book is that it was way, way too short. I really enjoyed it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mme Proust and the kosher kitchen</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/mme-proust-and-the-kosher-kitchen-by-kate-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/mme-proust-and-the-kosher-kitchen-by-kate-taylor/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Taylor, Kate
Title: Mme Proust and the kosher kitchen.
Publication: [Toronto] : Doubleday Canada, c2003. ISBN 978-0701173746.
DAISY audio format narrated by Nicki Scrimger. CELA library call number DA25030. 414 pages in the hardcover edition; 15 hrs., 41 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story I picked up this book because Kate Taylor, a Canadian author, has a new book coming out soon. The new one, Serial monogamy, will not be available on CELA for several more months, so I downloaded this one to try instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindred by Octavia E. Butler</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/kindred-by-octavia-e-butler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/kindred-by-octavia-e-butler/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Butler, Octavia E. (1947-2006)
Title: Kindred.
Publication: Boston : Beacon Press, 2003. ISBN 9781449876814.
DAISY audio format narrated by Kim Staunton. CELA library call number DA46431. 306 pages in the paperback edition; 10 hrs., 55 min. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the story of Dana, a young African-American woman living in California in 1976, who is mysteriously and uncontrollably called to Maryland, circa 1815, to save the life of a white slave-owner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The other queen by Philippa Gregory</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-other-queen-by-philippa-gregory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-other-queen-by-philippa-gregory/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Gregory, Philippa
Title: The other queen
Publication: London : HarperCollins, 2008. ISBN 9780007190348.
DAISY audio format narrated by Anne Glatt and Marc Rosen. CELA library call number DC34129. 442 pages in the paperback edition; 13 hrs., 37 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Set in the 16th century England of Elizabeth I, this historical novel tells the story of Mary, Queen of Scots (1542-1587).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lavinia by Ursula K. Le Guin</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/lavinia-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/lavinia-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Le Guin, Ursula K.
Title: Lavinia
Publication: Orlando : Harcourt, 2008. ISBN 9781456106621.
DAISY audio format narrated by Alyssa Bresnahan. CELA library call number DA47766. 293 pages in the paperback edition, 11 hrs., 39 min. as a recorded book.
About the story Ursula K. Le Guin has been one of my favourite authors ever since I encountered her Earthsea books as a young girl. They were among the books I could not wait to read to my daughter when she was younger, and they hold a special place in my heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Julia speaks her mind by Ann B. Ross</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/miss-julia-speaks-her-mind-by-ann-b-ross/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/miss-julia-speaks-her-mind-by-ann-b-ross/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Ross, Ann B.
Title: Miss Julia speaks her mind
Publication: William Morrow, 2000. ISBN 9780061978302.
DAISY audio format narrated by Terry Hayes Sales. CELA library call number DA22137. 290 pages in the paperback edition, 8 hrs., 38 min. as a recorded book.
About the story In this, the first book in the Miss Julia series, the narrator Miss Julia jumps right in and tells the story of her small, Southern US town in the 1950s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>