<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Non Fiction on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</title>
    <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/categories/non-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Non Fiction on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://StackSquirrel.github.io/categories/non-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsettling Canada by Arthur Manuel</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/unsettling-canada-by-arthur-manuel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/unsettling-canada-by-arthur-manuel/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Manuel, Arthur with Grand Chief Ronald M. Derrickson, forward by Naomi Klein
Title: Unsettling Canada : A national wake-up call
Publication: Toronto : Between the Lines, 2015. ISBN 9781771131766.
DAISY audio format narrated by Ken Luginbuhl. CELA library call number DA50988. 266 pages in the paper edition; 12 hrs., 8 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Arthur Manuel has been on the front lines of the battle for the recognition of indigenous rights, and specifically aboriginal title to the land, all his life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peace pipe dreams by Darrell Dennis</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/peace-pipe-dreams-by-darrell-dennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/peace-pipe-dreams-by-darrell-dennis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Dennis, Darrell (Darrell Michael).
Title: Peace pipe dreams : The truth about lies about Indians.
Publication: Madeira Park, British Columbia : Douglas &amp;amp; McIntyre, 2014. ISBN 9781771000406.
DAISY audio format narrated by Bruce McLeod. CELA library call number DA50486. 240 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 8 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Everyone should read this book.
Winner of First Nation Communities Read 2015-2016, Shushwap writer Darrel Dennis starts out with some &amp;ldquo;myth-busting&amp;rdquo;, humourously debunking some popularly-held mainstream stereotypes about indigenous people in Canada: drunken Indians, lazy Indians, no taxes, free schooling and housing, that they get a free ride&amp;hellip; there are so very many.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Cathcart&#39;s greek philosopher joke books</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/thomas-cathcarts-greek-philosopher-joke-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/thomas-cathcarts-greek-philosopher-joke-books/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cathcart, Thomas (1940- ) and Daniel Klein.
Title: Plato and a platypus walk into a bar&amp;hellip;: Understanding philosophy through jokes. (2006)
Publication: New York : Abrams Image, 2006. ISBN 9781456102821.
DAISY audio format narrated by Johnny Heller. CELA library call number DC46041. 224 pages in the paperback edition; 4 hrs., 9 min. as a recorded book.
Title: Aristotle and an aardvark go to Washington: Understanding political doublespeak through philosophy and jokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five minds of the future by Robert Gardner</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/five-minds-for-the-future-by-howard-gardner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/five-minds-for-the-future-by-howard-gardner/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Gardner, Howard. Title: Five minds for the future. Publication: Boston, Mass. : Harvard Business School Press, c2007. ISBN 9781591399124.
196 pages in the paper edition; 6hrs., 15 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story American developmental psychologist Howard Gardner, Hobbs Professor of Cognition and Education at the Harvard Graduate School of Education, wrote this book to describe the intellectual skills and the type of learning he thinks will be necessary to succeed in the workplace of the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian copyright: A citizen&#39;s guide</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/canadian-copyright-a-citizens-guide-by-laura-murray/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/canadian-copyright-a-citizens-guide-by-laura-murray/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Murray, Laura J. with Samuel E. Trosow
Title: Canadian copyright: A citizen&amp;rsquo;s guide. (2nd edition)
Publication: Toronto : Between the Lines, 2013. ISBN 9781771130134.
About the book I initially read the first edition of this book in 2007. I was struck by how clearly the authors explained the history of copyright in Canada. They clearly demonstrate how that history informs Canadian law, and how the law informs the practice of individuals and groups across our society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UContent by Nicholas Toaiuolo</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/ucontent-by-nicholas-tomaiuolo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/ucontent-by-nicholas-tomaiuolo/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Tomaiuolos, Nicholas G.
Title: UContent: The information professional&amp;rsquo;s guide to user-generated content.
Publication: Medford, N.J.: Information Today, 2012. 340p. ISBN 9781573874250
About the book User-education librarian and information-literacy instructor Nicholas Tomaiuolo presents an overview of the major &amp;ldquo;Web 2.0&amp;rdquo; resources and how librarians might and have used them.
Because of the fungible nature of his material, he provides a companion website which he commits to updating with resources as they move or become available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some great idea by Edward Keenan</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/some-great-idea-by-edward-keenan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/some-great-idea-by-edward-keenan/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Keenan, Edward
Title: Some great idea: good neighbourhoods, crazy politics and the invention of Toronto.
Publication: Toronto : Coach House Books, c2013. 175 p. ISBN: 9781552452660.
About the book This small, readable book by Toronto journalist Edward Keenan did something I thought could never happen &amp;ndash; it made the election of Toronto mayor Rob Ford almost make sense!
Starting with a number &amp;ldquo;Toronto stories&amp;rdquo;, including his meeting with then-Councillor Rob Ford in 2006, Keenan uses story to describe different facets and ways of life the city of Toronto.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>