<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supernatural on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</title>
    <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/tags/supernatural/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supernatural on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dmacleod.ca/ra/tags/supernatural/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A discovery of witches by Deborah E. Harkness (All souls trilogy)</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/a-discovery-of-witches-by-deborah-e-harkness-all-souls-trilogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/a-discovery-of-witches-by-deborah-e-harkness-all-souls-trilogy/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Harkness, Deborah E., 1965-
Title: A discovery of witches; Series: All souls trilogy
 A discovery of witches (DA41609, ISBN9780670022410), 2011, read by Imogen Church (579 pages ; 25 hours, 31 minutes) Shadow of the night (DA45810, ISBN9780670023486), 2012, read by Karina Fernandez (584 pages ; 25 hours, 22 minutes) The book of life (DA49922, ISBN9780670025596 ), 2014, read by Jennifer Ikeda (561 pages; 23 hours, 55 minutes)  Publication: New York : Viking, 2011, 2012 &amp;amp; 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The untold by Courtney Collins</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-untold-by-courtney-collins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-untold-by-courtney-collins/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Collins, Courtney.
Title: The untold
Publication: New York : Amy Einhorn Books, Published by G.P. Putnam&amp;rsquo;s Sons, a member of Penguin Group (USA), 2014. ISBN 9780399167096.
DAISY audio format narrated by the author. CELA library call number DA49956. 288 pages in the paper edition; 6 hrs., 56 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Based on the true story of Elizabeth Jessie Hickman, a woman who rustled cattle and escaped a brutal life, fleeing into the wilderness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosstalk by Connie Willis</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/crosstalk-by-connie-willis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/crosstalk-by-connie-willis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Willis, Connie.
Title: Crosstalk.
Publication: New York : Del Rey, [2016]. ISBN 9780345540676.
DAISY audio format narrated by Mia Barron. CELA library call number DA52655. 498 pages in the paper edition; 18 hrs., 45 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This book follows the adventures of young Briddey Flanagan, an Irish-American woman living in a modern day where doctors have the ability to surgically increase empathy between romantic partners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Swallow: A ghost story by Charis Cotter</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-swallow-a-ghost-story-by-charis-cotter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-swallow-a-ghost-story-by-charis-cotter/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cotter, Charis.
Title: The swallow : A ghost story
Publication: Toronto : Tundra Books, 2014. ISBN 9781770495913.
DAISY audio format available on Bookshare. It is not available on the CELA library (yet). 320 pages in the paper edition.
About the story OK, I fell off the blogging wagon for a bit, there.
Ironically, it was Ursula K. LeGuin&amp;rsquo;s WONDERFUL collection of novellas, The Found and the Lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thornyhold by Mary Stewart</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/thornyhold-by-mary-stewart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/thornyhold-by-mary-stewart/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Stewart, Mary.
Title: Thornyhold.
Publication: London ; Toronto : Hodder &amp;amp; Stoughton, 1988. ISBN 0688084257.
DAISY audio format narrated by Pauline Munro. CELA library call number DA33092. 224 pages in the paperback edition; 6 hrs., 59 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story The first thing I want to say about this book is that it was way, way too short. I really enjoyed it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lavinia by Ursula K. Le Guin</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/lavinia-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/lavinia-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Le Guin, Ursula K.
Title: Lavinia
Publication: Orlando : Harcourt, 2008. ISBN 9781456106621.
DAISY audio format narrated by Alyssa Bresnahan. CELA library call number DA47766. 293 pages in the paperback edition, 11 hrs., 39 min. as a recorded book.
About the story Ursula K. Le Guin has been one of my favourite authors ever since I encountered her Earthsea books as a young girl. They were among the books I could not wait to read to my daughter when she was younger, and they hold a special place in my heart.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>