<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social History on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</title>
    <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/tags/social-history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social History on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://StackSquirrel.github.io/tags/social-history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsettling Canada by Arthur Manuel</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/unsettling-canada-by-arthur-manuel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/unsettling-canada-by-arthur-manuel/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Manuel, Arthur with Grand Chief Ronald M. Derrickson, forward by Naomi Klein
Title: Unsettling Canada : A national wake-up call
Publication: Toronto : Between the Lines, 2015. ISBN 9781771131766.
DAISY audio format narrated by Ken Luginbuhl. CELA library call number DA50988. 266 pages in the paper edition; 12 hrs., 8 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Arthur Manuel has been on the front lines of the battle for the recognition of indigenous rights, and specifically aboriginal title to the land, all his life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obasan-by-joy-kogawa</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/obasan-by-joy-kogawa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/obasan-by-joy-kogawa/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Kogawa, Joy
Title: Obasan.
Publication: Toronto : Lester &amp;amp; Orpen Dennys, 1981. ISBN 0-919630-42-1.
DAISY audio format narrated by the author. CELA library call number DA03222. 250 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 51 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Beautifully read by the author, Obasan tells the story of the internment of Japanese-Canadians during the Second World War.
Her narrator, Naomi Nakane (pronounced na-kaan-neh), is a middle-aged schoolteacher on the Canadian prairies at the time the story opens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peace pipe dreams by Darrell Dennis</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/peace-pipe-dreams-by-darrell-dennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/peace-pipe-dreams-by-darrell-dennis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Dennis, Darrell (Darrell Michael).
Title: Peace pipe dreams : The truth about lies about Indians.
Publication: Madeira Park, British Columbia : Douglas &amp;amp; McIntyre, 2014. ISBN 9781771000406.
DAISY audio format narrated by Bruce McLeod. CELA library call number DA50486. 240 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 8 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Everyone should read this book.
Winner of First Nation Communities Read 2015-2016, Shushwap writer Darrel Dennis starts out with some &amp;ldquo;myth-busting&amp;rdquo;, humourously debunking some popularly-held mainstream stereotypes about indigenous people in Canada: drunken Indians, lazy Indians, no taxes, free schooling and housing, that they get a free ride&amp;hellip; there are so very many.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The last Neanderthal by Clarie Cameron</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-last-neanderthal-by-clarie-cameron/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-last-neanderthal-by-clarie-cameron/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cameron, Claire, 1973-
Title: The last Neanderthal.
Publication: City : Press, year.Toronto : Doubleday Canada, 2017. ISBN 9780385686785.
276 pages in the print edition.
About the story This is a forthcoming book, which I read as a galley proof. I used the Adobe Digital Editions reader to read this DRM e-book, with NVDA (NonVisual Desktop Access) a by-donation screen reader that allows blind and visually-impaired people use computers and the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magruder&#39;s curiosity cabinet by HP Wood</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/magruders-curiosity-cabinet-by-hp-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/magruders-curiosity-cabinet-by-hp-wood/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Wood, H. P. (Hilary Poole).
Title: Magruder&amp;rsquo;s curiosity cabinet.
Publication: Naperville, IL : Sourcebooks Landmark, 2016. ISBN 9781501908415.
DAISY audio format narrated by Nancy Wu. CELA library call number DA52319. 368 pages in the print edition; 13 hrs., 1 min. as a recorded book.
About the story I had no idea what to expect from this book, and I must say: I&amp;rsquo;m delighted!
Set in the amusement parks of Coney Island in 1904, the main characters are the sideshow &amp;ldquo;freaks&amp;rdquo; and their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The virgin cure by Ami McKay</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/virgin-cure-by-ami-mckay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/virgin-cure-by-ami-mckay/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: McKay, Ami
Title: The virgin cure
Publication: Toronto : Knopf Canada, 2010. ISBN 9780676979565.
DAISY audio format narrated by Jennifer Coffey. CELA library call number DA41472. 368 pages in the hardcover edition; 9 hrs., 30 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story I read Ami McKay&amp;rsquo;s first book, The birth House, many years ago and loved it. This is her second novel.
Set in New York city in 1871, the book follows the life of a young girl named Moth who lives in poverty with her mother on Christie Street, a poor area without sewers where people live in squalor as they can and die when they can no longer hold the tatters of their lives together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dispossessed: An ambiguous utopia by Ursula K. Le Guin</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-dispossessed-an-ambiguous-utopia-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-dispossessed-an-ambiguous-utopia-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Le Guin, Ursula K., 1929-
Title: The dispossessed: An ambiguous utopia
Publication: New York : Harper &amp;amp; Row, [1974]. ISBN 0060125632.
DAISY audio format narrated by Lloyd Scott. CELA library call number DC03870. 341 pages in the paperback edition; 12 hrs., 9 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Set in Le Guin&amp;rsquo;s Hainish universe, this is the story of a physicist born into a radically democratic society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some great idea by Edward Keenan</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/some-great-idea-by-edward-keenan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/some-great-idea-by-edward-keenan/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Keenan, Edward
Title: Some great idea: good neighbourhoods, crazy politics and the invention of Toronto.
Publication: Toronto : Coach House Books, c2013. 175 p. ISBN: 9781552452660.
About the book This small, readable book by Toronto journalist Edward Keenan did something I thought could never happen &amp;ndash; it made the election of Toronto mayor Rob Ford almost make sense!
Starting with a number &amp;ldquo;Toronto stories&amp;rdquo;, including his meeting with then-Councillor Rob Ford in 2006, Keenan uses story to describe different facets and ways of life the city of Toronto.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>