<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Canada on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</title>
    <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/tags/canada/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Canada on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dmacleod.ca/ra/tags/canada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The back of the turtle by Thomas King</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-back-of-the-turtle-by-thomas-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-back-of-the-turtle-by-thomas-king/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: King, Thomas, 1943-
Title: The back of the turtle.
Publication: Toronto : HarperCollins Canada, 2014. ISBN 9781443431620.
DAISY audio format narrated by Jennifer Coffey. CELA library call number DA50031. 518 pages in the paper edition; 11 hrs., 41 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Set in the near future, following an apocalyptic environmental disaster, this is the story of a CEO, a scientist and a young First Nations artist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool water by Dianne Warren</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/cool-water-by-dianne-warren/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/cool-water-by-dianne-warren/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Warren, Dianne, 1950-
Title: Cool water by Dianne Warren
Publication: Toronto : HarperCollins Canada, 2009. ISBN 9781554685585.
DAISY audio format narrated by Kathleen Miller. CELA library call number DA38309. 328 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 50 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Set in the small town of Juliet, Saskatchewan, this book is a series of short stories that, together, build a multi-dimensional picture of the town&amp;rsquo;s inhabitants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The story of Owen, dragon slayer of Trondheim</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-story-of-owen-dragon-slayer-of-trondheim-by-ek-johnston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-story-of-owen-dragon-slayer-of-trondheim-by-ek-johnston/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Johnston, E. K.
Title: The story of Owen : Dragon slayer of Trondheim
Publication: Minneapolis : Carolrhoda Lab, [2014]. ISBN 9781467710664.
DAISY audio format. 305 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 25 mins. as a recorded book. Not available through CELA.
About the story This is a Canadian book, set in Southwestern Ontario on the shores of Lake Huron. Picture an epic battle between a dragon and its Slayer … on the Burlington Skyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural order by Brian Francis</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/natural-order-by-brian-francis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/natural-order-by-brian-francis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Francis, Brian, 1971-
Title: Natural order
Publication: Toronto : Doubleday Canada, 2011. ISBN 9780385671538.
DAISY audio format narrated by Bennett McCardle. CELA library call number DA41407. 361 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 39 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the beautifully moving life story of an 86-year-old woman named Joyce. Told in a series of flash-backs from her early girlhood in rural Southern Ontario, through her marriage and family life, to her widowhood and eventual death, it shows the evolution of a life filled with regret and fear of what the neighbours will think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peace pipe dreams by Darrell Dennis</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/peace-pipe-dreams-by-darrell-dennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/peace-pipe-dreams-by-darrell-dennis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Dennis, Darrell (Darrell Michael).
Title: Peace pipe dreams : The truth about lies about Indians.
Publication: Madeira Park, British Columbia : Douglas &amp;amp; McIntyre, 2014. ISBN 9781771000406.
DAISY audio format narrated by Bruce McLeod. CELA library call number DA50486. 240 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 8 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Everyone should read this book.
Winner of First Nation Communities Read 2015-2016, Shushwap writer Darrel Dennis starts out with some &amp;ldquo;myth-busting&amp;rdquo;, humourously debunking some popularly-held mainstream stereotypes about indigenous people in Canada: drunken Indians, lazy Indians, no taxes, free schooling and housing, that they get a free ride&amp;hellip; there are so very many.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian copyright: A citizen&#39;s guide</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/canadian-copyright-a-citizens-guide-by-laura-murray/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/canadian-copyright-a-citizens-guide-by-laura-murray/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Murray, Laura J. with Samuel E. Trosow
Title: Canadian copyright: A citizen&amp;rsquo;s guide. (2nd edition)
Publication: Toronto : Between the Lines, 2013. ISBN 9781771130134.
About the book I initially read the first edition of this book in 2007. I was struck by how clearly the authors explained the history of copyright in Canada. They clearly demonstrate how that history informs Canadian law, and how the law informs the practice of individuals and groups across our society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some great idea by Edward Keenan</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/some-great-idea-by-edward-keenan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/some-great-idea-by-edward-keenan/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Keenan, Edward
Title: Some great idea: good neighbourhoods, crazy politics and the invention of Toronto.
Publication: Toronto : Coach House Books, c2013. 175 p. ISBN: 9781552452660.
About the book This small, readable book by Toronto journalist Edward Keenan did something I thought could never happen &amp;ndash; it made the election of Toronto mayor Rob Ford almost make sense!
Starting with a number &amp;ldquo;Toronto stories&amp;rdquo;, including his meeting with then-Councillor Rob Ford in 2006, Keenan uses story to describe different facets and ways of life the city of Toronto.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>