<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Humour on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</title>
    <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/tags/humour/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Humour on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://StackSquirrel.github.io/tags/humour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flavia de Luce books by Alan Bradley</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/flavia-de-luce-books-by-alan-bradley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/flavia-de-luce-books-by-alan-bradley/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Bradley, Alan C., 1938-
Title: The sweetness at the bottom of the pie.
Publication: New York : Bantam, 2009. ISBN 9780553840766.
DAISY audio format narrated by Annabel Bates. CELA library call number DA38056. 292 pages in the paper edition; 11 hrs., 9 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story If you have never read the Flavia de Luce (that&amp;rsquo;s Flavia with an eh) books, you are in for a wildly hilarious treat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s explore diabetes with owls by David Sedaris</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/lets-explore-diabetes-with-owls-by-david-sedaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/lets-explore-diabetes-with-owls-by-david-sedaris/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Sedaris, David.
Title: Let&amp;rsquo;s explore diabetes with owls: Essays, etc.
Publication: New York, NY : Little, Brown and Company, 2013. ISBN 9780316154697.
DAISY audio format narrated by David Sedaris. CELA library call number DA53190. 275 pages in the paper edition; 6 hrs., 26 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is a series of essays, read by the author and recorded at various times, some recorded live, some in studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peace pipe dreams by Darrell Dennis</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/peace-pipe-dreams-by-darrell-dennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/peace-pipe-dreams-by-darrell-dennis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Dennis, Darrell (Darrell Michael).
Title: Peace pipe dreams : The truth about lies about Indians.
Publication: Madeira Park, British Columbia : Douglas &amp;amp; McIntyre, 2014. ISBN 9781771000406.
DAISY audio format narrated by Bruce McLeod. CELA library call number DA50486. 240 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 8 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Everyone should read this book.
Winner of First Nation Communities Read 2015-2016, Shushwap writer Darrel Dennis starts out with some &amp;ldquo;myth-busting&amp;rdquo;, humourously debunking some popularly-held mainstream stereotypes about indigenous people in Canada: drunken Indians, lazy Indians, no taxes, free schooling and housing, that they get a free ride&amp;hellip; there are so very many.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Penguin anthology of Canadian humour by Will Ferguson</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-penguin-anthology-of-canadian-humour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-penguin-anthology-of-canadian-humour/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Ferguson, Will
Title: The Penguin anthology of Canadian humour
Publication: Toronto : Viking Canada, 2006. ISBN 9780670064434.
DAISY audio format narrated by Barbara Lord and Chris Caughey. CELA library call number DA28565. 496 pages in the print edition; 16 hrs., 45 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This anthology, compiled by Will Ferguson and originally published in 2006, is a veritable Who’s Who of Canadian humour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Woefield Farm books by Susan Juby</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-woefield-farm-books-by-susan-juby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/the-woefield-farm-books-by-susan-juby/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Juby, Susan (1969-)
Title: The Woefield poultry collective. Publication: New York : HarperCollins Canada, 2011. ISBN 9781554687442. DAISY audio format narrated by Jennifer Coffey. CELA library call number DA39138. 306 pages; 9hrs., 13mins. as a recorded book.
Title: Republic of Dirt: a return to Woefield Farm. Publication: Toronto : HarperAvenue 2015. ISBN 9781443423960. DAISY audio format narrated by Taina Makinen and Henry LaCroix. CELA library call number DA52124.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Cathcart&#39;s greek philosopher joke books</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/thomas-cathcarts-greek-philosopher-joke-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/thomas-cathcarts-greek-philosopher-joke-books/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cathcart, Thomas (1940- ) and Daniel Klein.
Title: Plato and a platypus walk into a bar&amp;hellip;: Understanding philosophy through jokes. (2006)
Publication: New York : Abrams Image, 2006. ISBN 9781456102821.
DAISY audio format narrated by Johnny Heller. CELA library call number DC46041. 224 pages in the paperback edition; 4 hrs., 9 min. as a recorded book.
Title: Aristotle and an aardvark go to Washington: Understanding political doublespeak through philosophy and jokes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>