<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United States on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</title>
    <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/tags/united-states/</link>
    <description>Recent content in United States on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dmacleod.ca/ra/tags/united-states/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Last ballad by Wiley Cash</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/last-ballad-by-wiley-cash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/last-ballad-by-wiley-cash/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Cash, Wiley
Title: The last ballad: A novel
Publication: New York, NY : William Morrow, an imprint of HarperCollins Publishers, 2017. ISBN 9780062682031.
DAISY audio format narrated by Karen Elizabeth White and Elizabeth Wiley. CELA library call number DA54667. 384 pages in the paper edition; 14 hrs., 7 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is a very moving story about, Ella Mae Wiggins, a striker and songwriter who took part in the 1929 textile mill strikes in the Southern United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No time to spare by Ursula K. Le Guin</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/no-spare-time-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/no-spare-time-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Le Guin, Ursula K., 1929-
Title: No time to spare : Thinking about what matters
Publication: Boston : Houghton Mifflin Harcourt, 2017. ISBN 9781328661593.
Not yet available in DAISY format. 280 pages in the paper edition.
About the story I read this book in pre-publication, in PDF format, using NVDA.
This book is the &amp;ldquo;the best of&amp;rdquo; Ursula K. Le Guin’s blog, which I have been loving for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s explore diabetes with owls by David Sedaris</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/lets-explore-diabetes-with-owls-by-david-sedaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/lets-explore-diabetes-with-owls-by-david-sedaris/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Sedaris, David.
Title: Let&amp;rsquo;s explore diabetes with owls: Essays, etc.
Publication: New York, NY : Little, Brown and Company, 2013. ISBN 9780316154697.
DAISY audio format narrated by David Sedaris. CELA library call number DA53190. 275 pages in the paper edition; 6 hrs., 26 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is a series of essays, read by the author and recorded at various times, some recorded live, some in studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cherry Cola book club by Ashton Lee</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-cherry-cola-book-club-by-ashton-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-cherry-cola-book-club-by-ashton-lee/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author:
Title: The Cherry Cola book club. Series: Cherry Cola Book Club ; 1
Publication: New York : Kensington Pub. Corp., 2013. ISBN 9780758273413.
DAISY audio format narrated by Marguerite Gavin. CELA library call number DA52856. 260 pages in the print edition; 7 hrs., 40 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story I picked this one up because it was the first in a series. I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t, because the title seemed a bit twee, but obviously I changed my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magruder&#39;s curiosity cabinet by HP Wood</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/magruders-curiosity-cabinet-by-hp-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/magruders-curiosity-cabinet-by-hp-wood/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Wood, H. P. (Hilary Poole).
Title: Magruder&amp;rsquo;s curiosity cabinet.
Publication: Naperville, IL : Sourcebooks Landmark, 2016. ISBN 9781501908415.
DAISY audio format narrated by Nancy Wu. CELA library call number DA52319. 368 pages in the print edition; 13 hrs., 1 min. as a recorded book.
About the story I had no idea what to expect from this book, and I must say: I&amp;rsquo;m delighted!
Set in the amusement parks of Coney Island in 1904, the main characters are the sideshow &amp;ldquo;freaks&amp;rdquo; and their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The hum and the shiver by Alex Bledsoe</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-hum-and-the-shiver-by-alex-bledsoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/the-hum-and-the-shiver-by-alex-bledsoe/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Bledsoe, Alex.
Title: The hum and the shiver.
Publication: New York : Tor Books, 2011. ISBN 9781455113965.
DAISY audio format narrated by Emily Janice Card and Stefan Rudnicki. CELA library call number DC52543. 349 pages in the paperback edition; 9 hrs., 44 mins. as a recorded book.
Title: The hum and the shiver.
Publication: New York : Tor Books, 2013. ISBN 9781482915600.
DAISY audio format narrated by Stefan Rudnicki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The virgin cure by Ami McKay</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/virgin-cure-by-ami-mckay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/virgin-cure-by-ami-mckay/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: McKay, Ami
Title: The virgin cure
Publication: Toronto : Knopf Canada, 2010. ISBN 9780676979565.
DAISY audio format narrated by Jennifer Coffey. CELA library call number DA41472. 368 pages in the hardcover edition; 9 hrs., 30 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story I read Ami McKay&amp;rsquo;s first book, The birth House, many years ago and loved it. This is her second novel.
Set in New York city in 1871, the book follows the life of a young girl named Moth who lives in poverty with her mother on Christie Street, a poor area without sewers where people live in squalor as they can and die when they can no longer hold the tatters of their lives together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindred by Octavia E. Butler</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/kindred-by-octavia-e-butler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/kindred-by-octavia-e-butler/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Butler, Octavia E. (1947-2006)
Title: Kindred.
Publication: Boston : Beacon Press, 2003. ISBN 9781449876814.
DAISY audio format narrated by Kim Staunton. CELA library call number DA46431. 306 pages in the paperback edition; 10 hrs., 55 min. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the story of Dana, a young African-American woman living in California in 1976, who is mysteriously and uncontrollably called to Maryland, circa 1815, to save the life of a white slave-owner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Julia speaks her mind by Ann B. Ross</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/miss-julia-speaks-her-mind-by-ann-b-ross/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/miss-julia-speaks-her-mind-by-ann-b-ross/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Ross, Ann B.
Title: Miss Julia speaks her mind
Publication: William Morrow, 2000. ISBN 9780061978302.
DAISY audio format narrated by Terry Hayes Sales. CELA library call number DA22137. 290 pages in the paperback edition, 8 hrs., 38 min. as a recorded book.
About the story In this, the first book in the Miss Julia series, the narrator Miss Julia jumps right in and tells the story of her small, Southern US town in the 1950s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>