<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1980s on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</title>
    <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/tags/1980s/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1980s on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dmacleod.ca/ra/tags/1980s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsettling Canada by Arthur Manuel</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/unsettling-canada-by-arthur-manuel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/unsettling-canada-by-arthur-manuel/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Manuel, Arthur with Grand Chief Ronald M. Derrickson, forward by Naomi Klein
Title: Unsettling Canada : A national wake-up call
Publication: Toronto : Between the Lines, 2015. ISBN 9781771131766.
DAISY audio format narrated by Ken Luginbuhl. CELA library call number DA50988. 266 pages in the paper edition; 12 hrs., 8 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Arthur Manuel has been on the front lines of the battle for the recognition of indigenous rights, and specifically aboriginal title to the land, all his life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chief Inspector Barnaby mysteries by Caroline Graham</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/chief-inspector-barnaby-mysteries-by-caroline-graham/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/chief-inspector-barnaby-mysteries-by-caroline-graham/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Graham, Caroline, 1931-
Title: The killings at Badger&amp;rsquo;s Drift Publication: London : Headline Book Publishing, 1989. ISBN 9780755342150. DAISY audio format narrated by Hugh Ross. CELA library call number DA31505. 264 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 26 mins. as a recorded book.
Title: A ghost in the machine. Publication: London : Headline, 2004. ISBN 0755307704. DAISY audio format narrated by Terri Cherniak. CELA library call number DA26166.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural order by Brian Francis</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/natural-order-by-brian-francis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/natural-order-by-brian-francis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Francis, Brian, 1971-
Title: Natural order
Publication: Toronto : Doubleday Canada, 2011. ISBN 9780385671538.
DAISY audio format narrated by Bennett McCardle. CELA library call number DA41407. 361 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 39 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the beautifully moving life story of an 86-year-old woman named Joyce. Told in a series of flash-backs from her early girlhood in rural Southern Ontario, through her marriage and family life, to her widowhood and eventual death, it shows the evolution of a life filled with regret and fear of what the neighbours will think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mme Proust and the kosher kitchen</title>
      <link>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/mme-proust-and-the-kosher-kitchen-by-kate-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmacleod.ca/ra/posts/mme-proust-and-the-kosher-kitchen-by-kate-taylor/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Taylor, Kate
Title: Mme Proust and the kosher kitchen.
Publication: [Toronto] : Doubleday Canada, c2003. ISBN 978-0701173746.
DAISY audio format narrated by Nicki Scrimger. CELA library call number DA25030. 414 pages in the hardcover edition; 15 hrs., 41 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story I picked up this book because Kate Taylor, a Canadian author, has a new book coming out soon. The new one, Serial monogamy, will not be available on CELA for several more months, so I downloaded this one to try instead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>