<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1950s on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</title>
    <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/tags/1950s/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1950s on Readers&#39; Advisory blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://StackSquirrel.github.io/tags/1950s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Itsuka by Joy Kogawa</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/itsuka-by-joy-kogawa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/itsuka-by-joy-kogawa/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Kogawa, Joy
Title: Itsuka
Publication: Toronto, Ont. : Viking, 1992. ISBN 0140169881.
DAISY audio format narrated by Sandra Scott. CELA library call number DA12414. 288 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 45 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the sequel to Obasan, which I reviewed earlier.
I must say that, at this point, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it holds a candle to the original but then it did not benefit from Joy Kogawa&amp;rsquo;s luminous reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La fiancée américaine d&#39;Éric Dupont</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/la-fiancee-americaine-eric-dupont/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/la-fiancee-americaine-eric-dupont/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Dupont, Éric, 1970-
Title: La fiancée américaine : roman
Publication: Montréal : Marchand de feuilles, 2012. ISBN 9782923896151.
DAISY audio format narrated by an unidentified narrator. CELA library call number DA96940. 557 pages in the paper edition; 25 hrs., 23 mins. as a recorded book.
À propos Une soirée du temps des fêtes à Rivière-du-Loup, Louis « le Cheval » Lamontagne raconte l&amp;rsquo;histoire de sa naissance à ses trois enfants tout en buvant du gin, en écoutant le chapelet à la radio, et en guettant le retour de sa femme de « chez les soeurs ».</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obasan-by-joy-kogawa</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/obasan-by-joy-kogawa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/obasan-by-joy-kogawa/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Kogawa, Joy
Title: Obasan.
Publication: Toronto : Lester &amp;amp; Orpen Dennys, 1981. ISBN 0-919630-42-1.
DAISY audio format narrated by the author. CELA library call number DA03222. 250 pages in the paper edition; 8 hrs., 51 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story Beautifully read by the author, Obasan tells the story of the internment of Japanese-Canadians during the Second World War.
Her narrator, Naomi Nakane (pronounced na-kaan-neh), is a middle-aged schoolteacher on the Canadian prairies at the time the story opens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flavia de Luce books by Alan Bradley</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/flavia-de-luce-books-by-alan-bradley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/flavia-de-luce-books-by-alan-bradley/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Bradley, Alan C., 1938-
Title: The sweetness at the bottom of the pie.
Publication: New York : Bantam, 2009. ISBN 9780553840766.
DAISY audio format narrated by Annabel Bates. CELA library call number DA38056. 292 pages in the paper edition; 11 hrs., 9 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story If you have never read the Flavia de Luce (that&amp;rsquo;s Flavia with an eh) books, you are in for a wildly hilarious treat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural order by Brian Francis</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/natural-order-by-brian-francis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/natural-order-by-brian-francis/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Francis, Brian, 1971-
Title: Natural order
Publication: Toronto : Doubleday Canada, 2011. ISBN 9780385671538.
DAISY audio format narrated by Bennett McCardle. CELA library call number DA41407. 361 pages in the paper edition; 9 hrs., 39 mins. as a recorded book.
About the story This is the beautifully moving life story of an 86-year-old woman named Joyce. Told in a series of flash-backs from her early girlhood in rural Southern Ontario, through her marriage and family life, to her widowhood and eventual death, it shows the evolution of a life filled with regret and fear of what the neighbours will think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Julia speaks her mind by Ann B. Ross</title>
      <link>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/miss-julia-speaks-her-mind-by-ann-b-ross/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://StackSquirrel.github.io/posts/miss-julia-speaks-her-mind-by-ann-b-ross/</guid>
      <description>About the book Author: Ross, Ann B.
Title: Miss Julia speaks her mind
Publication: William Morrow, 2000. ISBN 9780061978302.
DAISY audio format narrated by Terry Hayes Sales. CELA library call number DA22137. 290 pages in the paperback edition, 8 hrs., 38 min. as a recorded book.
About the story In this, the first book in the Miss Julia series, the narrator Miss Julia jumps right in and tells the story of her small, Southern US town in the 1950s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>